Justin Pullman

Email: jpullman@iastate.edu Phone: (309) 414-7043 Portfolio: jpullman.com

SUMMARY Self-motivated soon to be new graduate with over 5 years of experience in team-based product design and fabrication. Demonstrated leadership skills in both small and large team group projects. Learning continuously, having a multidisciplinary background with expertise in CAD, programming, and microprocessors. Consistently recognized as a top performer with a strong work ethic and currently seeking a full-time position as an aerospace engineer.

EDUCATION

Iowa State University, Ames IA,

Anticipated Grad: December 2023

- Bachelor of Science in Aerospace Engineering
- GPA: 3.27 / 4.00

EXPERIENCE

Robotics Coach — Peoria Academy, Peoria, IL,

August 2019 - December 2019

- Instructed students in various engineering disciplines to teach the design process and fostered communication through hands-on activities.
- Motivated problem-solving by recognizing and rewarding innovative thinking to garner innovative solutions from students.
- Encouraged critical thinking by posing open-ended questions.

Mechatronics Internship—Caterpillar, Peoria, IL,

June 2018 - August 2018

- Utilized MATLAB and Simulink to perform hardware in the loop test configurations.
- Gained insight into engine model development by collaborating with industry engineers.
- Demonstrated attention to detail by compiling GPS data from diverse sources and formats.

LEADERSHIP & ACTIVITIES

Design Team Leader — Senior Design Project, Ames, IA,

January 2023 - Present

- Led a 4-person team in the iterative design of 2 small unmanned aerial vehicles.
- Distilled final product features and trade studies into technical level documentation.
- Presented technical material to clients.
- Conducted design reviews and planned task breakdowns.

Founding member — Autonomous Robotics Club (ARC), Ames, IA, Au

August 2022 - Present

- 3D modeled a competition ready robot using Autodesk Inventor
- Developed a virtual robot using Gazebo and ROS (Robot Operating System).
- Developed python code for autonomous mobile robots.

Mechanical Lead, Team Leader — FIRST Robotics Team, Peoria, IL, August 2015 - May 2019

- Led a 30-person team in the design and fabrication of a 150 lb. robot.
- Facilitated effective communication between departments.
- Headed up product management, keeping the team on task and on track.

SKILLS

- CAD Software: **CSWP SolidWorks**, Autodesk Inventor, Ansys
- Programming languages: Python, MATLAB, C, C++
- Proficient with Arduino, Raspberry Pi, and Linux.